现在让我们将翻译带入图片中。坐标框架A，坐标框架B
Now let's bring translation into the picture. Coordinate frame A, Coordinate frame B which
相对于坐标框架A和点P进行平移和旋转。我们可以表示
is translated and rotated with respect to coordinate frame A and a point P. We can represent
关于帧B的矢量的点P和该矢量可以用术语来描述
the point P by a vector with respect to frame B and that vector can be described in terms
其组件沿XB和YB轴。
of its components along the XB and YB axis.
现在我们可以将该矢量旋转到新帧，坐标框架V和坐标框架V.
Now we can rotate that vector into a new frame, coordinate frame V, and coordinate frame V
具有与坐标框架A平行的轴。我们已经讨论了如何操作
has axes which are parallel to coordinate frame A. We've already talked about how to
使用旋转矩阵将矢量从一个坐标系旋转到另一个坐标系。并作为
rotate a vector from one coordinate frame to another using a rotation matrix. And as
我们正确地写了这个表达式的健全性检查，我们注意到这两个B是
a sanity check that we've written this expression correctly, we noticed that these two Bs are
彼此相邻。这是好事。
next to each other. That's a good thing.
现在让我们描述坐标系V相对于坐标系A的原点
Now let's describe the origin of coordinate frame V with respect to coordinate frame A
我们用矢量做到了。这是从A到V的向量。现在我们可以添加向量
and we do that with a vector. That's a vector from A to V. Now we're allowed to add vectors
所以我们可以将这个矢量ATV添加到矢量VP，以获得描述该矢量的矢量
so we can add this vector ATV to the vector VP to obtain the vector that describes the
相对于坐标系A的点P.我们可以这样做，因为这两个向量是
point P with respect to coordinate frame A. We can do that because these two vectors are
关于其轴彼此平行的坐标框描述。一世
described with respect to coordinate frames whose axes are parallel to one another. I
可以用一个方程代替另一个方程并写出来。再次因为这两个
can substitute one equation into the other and write this. And again because these two
坐标框架是平行的我可以写这个。
coordinate frames are parallel I can write this.
让我们在这个表达式中展开向量和矩阵，并根据它们来编写它们
Let's expand the vectors and matrix in this expression and write them in terms of their
元素。现在我可以拉一点技巧，现在就像这样写。如果你是
elements. Now I can pull a little bit of a trick and now write it like this. If you're
不确定这个步骤，扩展矩阵并说服自己，他们是完全一样的。
unsure about this step, expand out the matrix and convince yourself that they are exactly the same.
现在这个表达式有一个双元素向量和一个三元素向量。
Now this expression has got a two-element vector and a three-element vector over here.
让我们把事情做得更加对称，然后像这样写。我们现在做了什么
Let's make things a little bit more symmetric and write it like this. What we've done now
将一些零和一些零添加到矩阵的底行。以前我们有2x2
is added some zeros and some ones to the bottom row of the matrix. Previously we had a 2x2
旋转矩阵。现在我们看到它嵌入到3x3矩阵的左上角。
rotation matrix. Now we see that that's embedded into the top left corner of a 3x3 matrix.
而我们过去拥有2个元素的向量现在有三个元素。我们可以写这个
And our vectors which used to have 2 elements now have three elements. We can write this
在这种形式下更简洁。符号，波浪线，小p上方表示
even more succinctly in this form. The notation, the tilde, above the little p indicates that
它是一个同质的向量。它有三个元素而不是两个，我们将讨论这个问题
it is a homogeneous vector. It has got three elements not two, and we'll talk about that
过了一会儿。关于坐标系A通过均匀来描述该点
in just a moment. The point is described with respect to coordinate frame A by a homogeneous
我们可以从关于坐标的点的均匀矢量获得的矢量
vector which we can obtain from the homogeneous vector of the point with respect to coordinate
帧B乘以该矩阵。
frame B multiplied by this matrix.
矩阵的元素包括旋转矩阵，它是方向的函数;
The elements of the matrix include the rotation matrix, which is the function of the orientation;
Theta，以及坐标系A的原点和坐标系之间的平移
Theta, and the translation between the origin of coordinate frame A and coordinate frame
B.我们在二维平面中有一个熟悉的矢量表示，两个数字
B. We have the familiar representation of a vector in a 2-dimensional plane, two numbers
A和B.均匀向量中有三个元素。它有A和B以及额外的
A and B. The homogeneous vector has got three elements in it. It's got A and B and an additional
设置为1的元素。这称为均匀变换。这是一个3x3
element which is set to 1. This we refer to as a homogeneous transformation. It is a 3x3
矩阵。均匀变换矩阵T包括2×2的旋转矩阵
matrix. The homogeneous transformation matrix T comprises a rotation matrix which is 2x2
和一个2x1矩阵的平移向量，用一对零和一个填充。
and a translation vector which is a 2x1 matrix padded out with a couple of zeros and a one.
该矩阵描述了相对姿势。它描述了关于姿势的姿势B.
This matrix describes a relative pose. It describes the pose B with respect to the pose
所有这些都是在这个单一的3x3矩阵中编码的。一位数学家会说
of A. All of that is encoded in this single 3x3 matrix. A mathematician would say that
齐次变换属于维数2的特殊欧几里得群。符号上
homogeneous transformation belongs to the special Euclidian group of dimension 2. Symbolically
我们可以说矩阵T属于集合SE（2）。
we would say matrix T belongs to the set SE(2).
最后，是时候开始使这些抽象概念成为现实。姿势只是一个矩阵。哪里
Finally it's time to start making these abstract concepts real. Pose is just a matrix. Where
在我们可以替换这个3x3齐次变换矩阵之前，我们有符号ksi。
we had the symbol ksi before we can substitute this 3x3 homogeneous transformation matrix.
当我们谈论使用O+算子将两个姿势复合或连接在一起时，
When we talk about compounding or joining two poses together using the O+ operator,
这与乘以这两个齐次变换完全相同。我们用的是
that is exactly the same as multiplying these two homogeneous transformations. We use the
O-运算符表示相对姿势的否定，这只是反过来
O- operator to indicate the negation of a relative pose, and that is simply the inverse
均匀变换矩阵我之前提到过旋转的倒数
of a homogeneous transformation matrix. I mentioned earlier that the inverse of a rotation
矩阵等于它的转置。对于均匀转换，情况并非如此
matrix is equal to its transpose. That is not the case for a homogeneous transformation
矩阵。您需要执行适当的矩阵逆：反转3x3矩阵。
matrix. You need to perform a proper matrix inverse: invert a 3x3 matrix.
我们引入了一个点运算符，它将矢量从一个坐标系转换为另一个坐标系。
We introduced a dot operator which transforms a vector from one coordinate frame to another.
这仅仅是均匀变换矩阵和所表示的矢量的乘积
And that is simply the product of the homogeneous transformation matrix and the vector represented
以同质的形式。请记住，均匀向量是从原始向量获得的
in homogeneous form. Remember that the homogeneous vector is obtained from the original vector
P，两个向量，我们增加或附加一个元素，以形成一个三元素
P, the two vector and we augment or append a one element to that to form a three element
向量。
vector.
这里我们在MATLAB中，我们将试验这些二维齐次变换
Here we are in MATLAB and we're going to experiment with these 2-dimensional homogeneous transformation
矩阵。所以我要做的是引入一个名为transl2的函数来创建一个
matrices. So what I’m going to do is introduce a function called transl2 which creates a
同质转换代表纯粹的翻译，即翻译
homogeneous transformation representing a pure translation, that is a translation of
x方向为1，y方向为2。
1 in the x direction and 2 in the y direction.
之前我们已经看到了如何创建一个二维旋转矩阵，例如旋转
Previously we saw how to create a 2-dimensional rotation matrix, for instance a rotation of
像这样创建30度。我们看到这个旋转矩阵只有2x2比较
30 degrees is created like this. We see that this rotation matrix is only 2x2 compared
到3x3齐次变换矩阵。所以我可以创建一个同质的转换
to the 3x3 homogeneous transformation matrix. So I can create a homogeneous transformation
通过前缀字母T来表示此旋转的矩阵。此函数返回一个
matrix equivalent of this rotation by prefixing with the letter T. This function returns a
3x3齐次变换矩阵。我们可以看到旋转矩阵部分在
3x3 homogeneous transformation matrix. We can see the rotation matrix part up in the
左上角。我们可以看到该矩阵的平移部分等于零。这个
top left corner. We can see that the translation part of this matrix is equal to zero. This
均匀变换矩阵表示纯旋转。
homogeneous transformation matrix represents a pure rotation.
现在我们可以将这两者相乘。transl2，乘以旋转部分-30度。
Now we can multiply these two together. transl2, Multiply it by the rotation part - 30 degrees.
现在我所拥有的是一个代表姿势的同质转换。
And now what I have is a homogeneous transformation which represents a pose.
它有一个旋转组件，它有一个平移组件。
It's got a rotational component and it's got a translational component.
现在工具箱有一个简写功能来实现这一目标。
Now the toolbox has got a shorthand function to achieve this.
我传入x和y平移部分;旋转部分和选项
I pass in the x and y translational parts; the rotational part and the option
说这个角度是以度为单位指定的。我们这里有完全相同的矩阵。
to say that that angle is specified in units of degrees. We have exactly the same matrix here.
现在让我们绘制这个特定的姿势并看看它的样子。要做到这一点，我要去
Now let's plot this particular pose and see what it looks like. And to do that I'm going
创建一个绘制轴的轴，x将从0-5变化，y将变为
to create an axis in which to plot, and x is going to vary from 0-5 and y is going to
从0-5不等。我需要设置宽高比，以便一切看起来都合理，所以我就是
vary from 0-5. I need to set the aspect ratio so that everything looks reasonable, so I'm
要设置轴，使宽高比为正方形。我要坚持因为
going to set the axis so that the aspect ratio is square. I'm going to put a hold on because
我要画一些姿势。我将要绘制的第一个姿势我要投入工作区
I'm going to plot a few poses. The first pose I'm going to plot I'm going to put into workspace
变量T1，它是我刚才看到的姿势：x方向1，
variable T1 and it is the pose that I looked at just a moment ago: 1 in the x direction,
2在y方向上旋转30度。有一个同质的转变
2 in the y direction and the rotation of 30 degrees. There is a homogeneous transformation
矩阵。现在我要描绘一下。
matrix. Now I'm going to plot that.
为了绘制我使用函数trplot2。2后缀意味着它是2维的
To plot that I use the function trplot2. The 2 suffix means that it's for 2-dimensional
构成。传递由均匀变换表示的姿势。我要去画情节
poses. Pass in the pose represented by the homogeneous transformation. I'm going to plot
它作为一个名为1的框架，我将以蓝色绘制它。有很多
it as a frame named 1, and I'm going to plot it in the color blue. There are quite a few
那里的选择。在那里我们看到了姿势。我们可以看到它确实有翻译
options there. And there we see the pose plotted. We can see that it does indeed have a translational
零件;x方向1，y方向2。并且它是相对旋转的
component; 1 in the x direction, 2 in the y direction. And it is rotated with respect
到世界坐标框架。
to the world coordinate frame.
我可以很容易地创建另一个姿势。我可以创建一个偏移量为的姿势
I can create another pose quite easily. I can create a pose that has got an offset of
在x方向上2。在y方向上1并且没有旋转。这就是同质的
2 in the x direction. 1 in the y direction and no rotation. That's what the homogeneous
转型看起来像。现在我要描绘一下。我将使用函数trplot2
transformation looks like. Now I'm going to plot that. I'm going to use the function trplot2
再次，传入齐次变换矩阵，我将把它绘制成一个帧
again, pass in the homogeneous transformation matrix, and I’m going to plot it as a frame
标记2.为了与众不同，我将把它描绘成一个红色的框架，我们在这里看到
labeled 2. To be different I'm going to plot it as a red colored frame, and here we see
第二个姿势。它没有轮换。它有一个翻译组件。
the second pose. It's got no rotation. It has got a translational component.
现在我可以构成其中的2个姿势。我要说姿势3等于姿势1复合
Now I can compose 2 of these poses. I’m going to say pose 3 is equal to pose 1 compounded
有姿势2.这就是转换矩阵的样子。我能描绘一下。我要去
with pose 2. That's what the transformation matrix looks like. I can plot that. I'm going
绘制一个trplot2，在矩阵中传递，将会有一个框架，称为3和
to plot that one, trplot2, pass in the matrix, there's going to be a frame, called 3 and
我要给那个绿色上色。因此，如果我复合那两个姿势，我最终得到了
I'm going to color that one green. So if I compound those 2 poses I end up with the
这里显示的姿势是3.我们想到这一点的方式是我们从世界框架中移开
pose shown here as 3. The way we can think about this is we moved from the world frame
从框架1旋转2，然后在框架1中，我们然后在x方向上移动2
2 from frame 1 which is rotated, and then in frame 1 we then moved 2 in the x direction
和y方向1。但是X和Y方向是第1帧，而不是世界框架
and 1 in the y direction. But X and Y direction are frame 1, not on the world frame, and that
将我们带到标记为第3帧的框架。
gets us to the frame labeled as frame 3.
我可以按相反的顺序复合姿势。我要创建一个新姿势T4和
I could compound the poses in the opposite order. I'm going to create a new pose T4 and
这将是姿势2与姿势1的复合。我们可以看到它是同质的
it's going to be pose 2 compounded with pose 1. We can see that's what the homogeneous
转换矩阵看起来像是与T3不同。我可以这样画。我可以通过
transformation matrix looks like and it's different to T3. I can plot this. I can pass
在T4。我可以将它绘制为标记为4的框架，我将以青色显示它。
in T4. I can plot it as a frame labeled 4 and I'm going to plot it in the color cyan.
在这里，我们可以看到框架4，它是由复合姿势2和后1组成的。现在我是
Here we can see the frame 4 which has resulted from compounding pose 2 with post 1. Now I'm
要在情节中引入一点。我要在坐标处引入一个点
going to introduce a point into the plot. I'm going to introduce a point at a coordinate
3,2。我需要转置它，使它成为列向量。它就是。我可以
3, 2. I need to transpose that so that it becomes a column vector. There it is. I can
情节。绘制点P，我将把它绘制成星号。在那里我们看到它
plot that. Plot point P, and I'm going to plot it as an asterisk. There we see it in
我们的数字。如果我想确定相对于第1帧的点的坐标那么
our figure. If I want to determine the coordinate of the point with respect to frame 1 then
我需要做的是使用相对姿势1的倒数，即，并乘以
what I need to do is to use the inverse of the relative pose 1, which is that, and multiply
它由均匀形式的点坐标组成。我会拿点P，我要追加
it by the points coordinate in homogeneous form. I'll take point P and I'm going to append
1到它。我现在拥有的是星号的齐次坐标
a 1 to it. What I have now is the homogeneous coordinate of the asterisk with respect to
坐标框架1。
the coordinate frame 1.